RAHEEL AHMED

Toronto Metropolitan University | Bachelor of Commerce

647-916-2111 | raheel.ahmedtr@gmail.com | Linkedin/Raheel-Ahmed-TMU

SUMMARY

Motivated and driven analyst with a strong interest in using technology to improve business processes. 4+ years of customer service expertise and a Bachelor of Commerce in Business Technology Management from TMU (formerly Ryerson University). Adept in team oriented environments with experience in various industries including IT, government, retail, and start-up.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Business Analyst | Virtek Solutions Inc. | Mississauga, ON | June 2022 - Current

- Analyzed business requirements, created processes with use case identification and sequence diagramming.
- Reported on performance metrics by identifying trends and using KPIs/KRIs.
- Maintained data to operational standards throughout the client lifecycle with use of programs such as Oracle, Excel, Microsoft Visio, SQL Server, and Power BI.

Project Manager | Ittehad Construction | Mississauga, ON | Mar 2022 - June 2022

- Completed the full project lifecycle for a reconstruction project within budget and scope.
- Outsourced sub-contract work and documented updates to a project sponsor.

OMNI Associate | Walmart Canada | Mississauga, ON | Feb 2018 - Mar 2022

- Provided exceptional customer service in 11 different operational units.
- Assisted in the launch of GHS and the implementation of autonomous grocery shopping, as well as improving online delivery options using data analysis of store survey scores.

Deputy Returning Officer | Elections Ontario | Mississauga, ON | Oct 2019

• Managed a single polling station for a condominium, handled multi-channel communications and tabulated all eligible votes to process and report to the local Elections Canada Office.

EDUCATION

BComm in Business Technology Management | TMU | Dec 2022

• Interdisciplinary degree combining project management, business analytics, and IT; involved in additional bootcamp certificates for SQL, Python, and Power of Excel.

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

WeDesignTech Hackathon (1st Place) | WITM Ted Rogers | Feb 2023

- Designed and pitched a user-friendly rental prototype built on Figma using UX design.
- 1 year funding further awarded at NSBE Hackathon with UofT Engineering.

ADaPT, Advanced Digital and Professional Training | Diversity Institute | Jan 2023

Developed skills in data analytics with Excel, web page development with HTML/CSS, SEO with Google Analytics, and UX Design Fundamentals.

Junior Achievement | RBC

Launched and marketed a start-up clothing brand to target multiple high schools.

SKILL SET

- Expertise in customer service and sales, with a background in project management and strong analytical acumen.
- Technical proficiency in Tableau, Power BI, MySQL, Microsoft Visio, and UML.